soft engineering radio episode 115
architecture analysis
[Music]
this is software engineering radio the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at se - radio dotnet
I see radio brings you relevant and
detailed discussions and interviews on
software engineering topics every 10
days thanks to our audience and the
partners listed on our website possible
[Music]
welcome to another episode of software
engineering radio this is an episode
about software architecture analysis and
today we're talking to Bob Marley
welcome Bob right so BOM hot well I was
about to say why don't you introduce
yourself to our listeners but we got
feedback which said that I shouldn't say
why don't you blah blah blah so please
introduce yourself to our listeners okay
thank you Marcus my name is pan America
I'm working at seek again the company
name is real also for English native
speakers so it's kind of funny but the
founder was Alan Thicke and we are
producing laser scanners mainly we are
the leader in the sensor area and my job
is in the central research and
development department software
engineering and responsible for tool
selection development processes all that
kind of stuff and in that context you
have been evaluating and working with
software conductor analysis tools in the
recent past that's that's right yes we
have looked at several tools and we had
also the problem that the software
architecture of our program decayed over
time and I think it's a common problem
right so the plan for this episode is to
first outline the problem which is
basically the the decay of software
architecture which all of you listeners
probably know is a problem and then
we're going to look at the analysis
tools and how they can help so why
should we care about software
architecture analysis I think in lots of
problems there happens architecture
decay or architectural erosion of
software and as we will see in we are
not alone in our projects we have also
some prominent representatives and even
some well-known projects like eclipse or
elect our nature some kind of
architectural erosion and the question
is how do you check architecture is
there some process is there some tool
that you are using and do you care about
at all I think in most projects when you
approach the release you will build in
workarounds things like that and you
will violate the original planned
software architecture and they don't you
will not remove that valuation yeah so
so the the thing we're going to look at
is that somebody and we're not going to
define who that is the architect or an
architect of team or an agile team
defines how the architecture should look
like and then we want to check whether
the actual code conforms to that
architect yes okay before we do that we
should probably define what architecture
is software architecture a definition I
like is from I Triple E and it says the
software architecture is a fundamental
organization of systems embodied it in
its components their relationship to
each other and the environment and the
principle governing its design and
evolution and I think the important
words are organization of the system
components the relationship between them
and the evolutionary part of the hell of
that process because that is the topic
where most problems arise during
projects defining an architecture is
easy yes keeping it alive during the
project is not that easy exactly and as
we shall see later on we will be able to
formulate those topics like organization
relationships in rules which you can
check against our current code base I
think there are two related topics we
should we should briefly mention to to
delineate from what we're doing today
one is that software architecture
documentation is not what we are talking
about writing a word document is not
verifiable right yeah
and the other thing is model term
development can you say something how
that relates I work the model driven
development and I'm also a big fan of
the model driven software development
process but I think it has also some
limitations especially on the tool side
there's not so much selection as
upcoming support as eclipse is open I
think things like that but they are
lots of project at least it's my
experience which are developed in the
say traditional way so we're out models
without code generators so people are
hacking code in the editor compiling it
and at some time they will violate the
UML diagrams some or model some other
people have drawn for them yeah and the
model driven software development
approach is a is it's very good in my
opinion but it has some open items for
example modeling language is for most
people UML is too general but there are
only few IDE switch really supposed the
DSL approaches with its own metamodel
etc also another problem is good
integration of legacy software so to
reverse engineer what do you get at
Edition as additional information from
the from the code level in the model you
need some kind of abstraction to gain
something in the model I think that's
that that's the central challenge I mean
if you do model driven then I guess the
need for a lot of this architecture
analysis goes away but if you do
classical approach or if you have legacy
systems then the model run approach
doesn't help you much and I even would
extend that argument even if you do
model driven software development you
have to verify with certain approach
that architecture is followed in your
model so you have some kind of model
verification that would be a different
tool yeah yeah so then let's look at the
core topic of this episode which is
architecture analysis you call it
architectural linting maybe you want to
explain where this comes from yes it
comes from the I think it's one of the
oldest tool in the software well that's
why I'm asking you our audience maybe
doesn't know yes the links tool is one
of the static code check us which is I
think around for about 20 years now it's
still there PC PC lint for checking c
and c++ code and the architectural
analysis is a static analysis approach
so I called it also linking software
architectures right
of course the static approach has some
limitations if you do things or tricks
at run time if you use reflection and
trauma on dll now in C++ you can have
some violations in your architecture
that you will not pray able to fine with
static analysis in the first approach
however there is some some tools that is
support that you can feed in information
about what reflection is you have a
class or used name cetera okay
to further structure the discussion you
have you have come up with a set of
levels or
kinds of architour of static analysis
and we can use that to explain what
we're doing here what we're not doing so
why don't I shouldn't say this I mean
it's probably true I say this too often
why don't you explain those levels so I
explain those levels no problem the goal
on all levels is to find and avoid
problems and to increase the quality and
also to measure it three different
levels we can distinguish in static
analysis the first I would call micro
level it's the really cold level we can
check with rule sets like miss Rossi it
concerns things like code layout records
risky statements that you should not do
in certain programming for now correct
the next level would be the macro level
these concerns things like class design
and rules you know from books like Scott
Myers jashub law is that right effective
c++ effective Java though that concerns
things like you should pass by
references things like that so actually
those macro level is more difficult to
check than the micro level because it
involves more intelligence or programmer
so tools
difficulties to check that or are some
kind of noisy at that level and the
interesting thing is at the next level
at architecture level things become
easier Agana on the architecture level
of static analysis we are talking about
layers graph architecture layer
architecture subsystem components
interfaces and things like coupling
between modules dependencies etc yep
and just to connect to the previous
episode on static analysis we've had
that basically looked at what you would
call the macro level mainly yes so that
was you know building a state based
model of other program class on that and
that stuff so um that's that's that and
today we're talking about the
architecture level what can you do with
architecture analysis we can do
different kinds of architectural answers
you could also call them different use
cases from architectural analysis one is
consistency analysis the idea is that
you check the intended architecture as
you are originally planted against the
existing architecture which is
effectively your code base right so you
find some some inconsistencies usually
between them and you have to deal with
them yeah the second one is rating an
architecture so you see something about
the internal software quality of your
architecture is there a high dependency
coupling do you have anti patterns bad
smells things like that the third one is
discovering architecture yeah maybe your
project lead or your architect from the
project has gone and there's no
documentation yeah it's not so uncommon
no I know case and then you have to
discover the possibly if there is one or
here is the reverse engineering yes then
another interesting topic is what I call
measured read effects and effectors this
is collecting some metrics about your
architecture accounting packages etc
it's important topic because you cannot
control what you cannot measure and I
think most of the people are not
measuring or do not collect
but at all arriving projects now okay
and the last one is monitoring changes
over time you have some trend the
architecture decreases packages I edit
coupling isn't increased when you
monitoring change you have a chance to
reverse the decay yep okay so we're
going to talk through each of those five
use cases we're going to start with the
consistency analysis as we said before
the idea is to check the existing code
structure against some kind of
architecture definition yeah that
requires that you somehow define what
the architecture should be how do you do
that you do that in a kind of
architectural language which is at the
moment tool specific and even some of
the tools when we come later to the
tools right we'll see that some of the
tools have even no way at the moment but
most of the tools fortunately have ways
to define the architecture so you don't
use you male or some other bonding
language what you do is you for example
in Java you collect a package to a
component and you say you are allowed to
have dependencies between component a
and component B or only between
interfaces to that component things like
that so so you define that a set of
packages you define that to be a
component and then you do dependency
analysis between those sets
aka components okay right that's the
idea so you define the shrewdest
architecture in some kind of modeling
let's call it modeling language or a
certain kind of architectural language
it's not so formal it's actually a set
of constraints yeah correct then you
extract the is architecture on the other
hand from your existing code base right
so to gain the real information from
from the process you have to have some
positive passes your your your byte code
or your C++ code and extracts its
architecture and then you do a
comparison and get it if I could take
two and derive some action and the
action would be you have to remove this
dependency to conform to the
architecture blah blah sometimes it may
be possible to
yeah I hate actual violation sometimes
it may even be impossible because you
have delivered the interfaces to some
client right and once you get these
actions what you basically do is you you
do refactoring of the architecture to to
to conform to the rules yes you do a
refactoring in the large we call just so
it's not a refactoring on the on the
attribute level or at a method level
essentially it's a refactoring on a
class level or package level or even
component level and you redesign for
example some packages you get
information how much violation do you
have and you can derive some strategies
for example if you have a bi-directional
dependency you can see where the number
is lower and try to remove and in one
way so of course what I what I really
want is you know in the Eclipse world to
control f1 or control one actually and
then quick fix and then fix my
architecture can the tools do that or is
it is it basically manual work to fix
the violation at the moment no the tools
could for trivial cases make some
suggestions or some hints but normally
the intelligence of the designer is
still needed now let me ask one thing I
am a little bit so okay so I am
skeptical about okay I do I well I agree
that these tools are useful no no no
discussion however I kind of object to
the idea as defining an architect to
just be a set of components and their
dependencies there is more to
Architecture than just dependencies so
my question is what kinds of constraints
can you actually define you said before
you have to do that you collect a bunch
of packages into what you call a
component and then you'd say from that
component that can only be two
dependencies two interfaces in that
other component what else can you do I
mean can you give us a couple of
examples of the kinds of things you can
check with these tools the tools even go
further as I said there are digital
aspects like for example anti patterns
or bad smells that you can detect so if
you have dependent base classes certain
tools are able to detect
and give you warning so you can remove
this or try to remove that that
anti-pattern also if you look at matrix
I think it's important to keep an eye on
yes on that area you usually make
threshold and identify some outliers of
that of that area and fix that classes
with too much public attribute things
like that what the tools give you is
basically an awareness of the problem
right but but you have to define what
the constraints are and you have to fix
the problems yourself so it identifies
the violation where it is the quantity
how much the impact has to be determined
by you and also if the handling of the
violations is possible the tool can
export a list with possible
modifications right so you fix them
later or you can even automate this
maybe in future and some tools even
allow you to do virtual refactoring that
you can move for example classes or
packages in advance huh and recompute
eight the violations on the virtual
refactoring so you don't do this
actually in the code you can't trust in
a simulation and look if it gets better
over us so the way this works is that
those tools actually parse the code into
some kind of data structure database and
you do the refactoring on that data
structure right and my experience was
that for example a lot of violations can
even be removed with moving some
packages or some classes to other levels
of a layered architecture right so I
guess that concludes the consistency
analysis part the next one was the
rating of architectures was that the
rating of architectures does not concern
any external requirements it concerns
the internal quality of your software so
do you have cycles in the in the
software is there what is the stability
do we have tight coupling and dependence
bad smells things like that so in that
case you don't define your own
constraints and architectural rules but
rather the tool comes with a set of
predefined smells yes the tool comes
with a predefined set of smells in the
under patterns right and it finds them
in your color other things you can look
for example is can I extract certain
things or my architecture or can certain
modules be reused independently yeah if
the tool comes with a set of predefined
anti patterns or smells can it do
automatic refactoring in that case then
no they're not yet there they can for
example detect dependent base class
which is a common undependable and the
interesting thing is that if you look at
real code for example on eclipse or jdk
you can find that on depend on dependent
base classes is merely two classes per
thousand in in Eclipse 2.1 and 16 per
thousand in jdk 1.4 but it's kind of
interesting if you apply those tools to
a large code base and again in that case
the tool gives you a list of problems
and/or diagrams or gives you makes you
aware of the problem and then you fix it
yes the representation are different
among the tools some tools represent
those things only numbers but some also
represent them in graphical ways because
sometimes one or the other approach is
more appropriate right so if you draw
for example the dependency of classes
and packages that depends on each other
for example in the JDK you see nearly a
big ball of mud right when you look at a
class that's about one time Dutch ah
yeah which say something about the
maintainability yeah it also says
something about the notation because it
doesn't help you much
too much information yes it's so much
information often the important point is
to get the right things so one important
point is to drill down for example from
component to package to class or the
actual violation where it happens and to
to go back to the to the top level so
that's a important point of aggregation
right right application of the
and presenting them IRA in numerical or
in graphical way so you can see the
violations on a very very macro level
and only if you want to know whether we
problem is you drill down right as
opposed to showing everything all the
time yes because then you lose your
lostness the next topic is discovering
an architecture again I think it's it's
mostly about making the users aware
visualizing things right yes sometimes
the architecture is they implicit so
there is no good documentation or the
architecture left the architect left the
project so you have no documentation of
the existing architecture and one use
case is discovering existing
architecture in your source code but
it's not the main usage of those tools
but it's a it's a possible use case back
in the days there was a tool called
sniff + + is it that kind of stuff it's
that kind kind of stuff but extended
with additional things like for example
craft layout for example if you look at
interfaces or derived class as you can
see which clients are using me am I used
in the right way which interfaces are
not used at all so I can adapt my API
and make additional design decisions
helps you find stuff that nobody uses so
you can't apricot remove it yes of
course you have a high level cross
reference like you had in sniff and
actually one of the creators of such
architectural analysis tool is what
which was back did the original sniff
implementation I take five ah I didn't
know that I knew that while the business
bug works on I think it's sort of cough
right yes so yes but I didn't know that
he was the sniff person yeah okay to
discover the arcade that well ok here's
the problem this covering the
architecture is the classical reverse
engineering problem because you want to
rediscover the intend of how the
architecture should look like from the
low level code and as we both know
that's not trivial so how good are these
tools what can they actually do is it
basically again defining components and
then
abstracting or aggregating things on
component-level they are pretty good at
that job I think because they're using
some kind of intelligent layout
mechanism for example if you look at
inheritance or core relationships can
apply different graph algorithms and see
the structure who used you see your your
central abstractions in a diagram on one
and and more concrete classes on the
other end so you can identify central
detection mechanisms so you're saying is
that one of the big advantage of these
tools that they give you a very good
visual clue of what's going on they
don't really infer much they really just
show you things in a way that you can
infer things yes solves the problem of
trying to understand what the original
person wanted men are the real facts
matrix use case number five I think
matrix are numbers and emotion also lie
but they can also say some kind of true
so metrics are for me indicators of
quality understandable ability
maintenance so measured numbers that can
say something about your existing code
base some trivial examples are lines of
code the climatic complexity and things
like that but I think more interesting
are metrics like invented from robot
Martine abstractness instability
inheritance death and things like that
number of overwritten or implemented
methods I guess the problem with metrics
is that there are so many of them so I
think that the challenge is to select
the right ones right the challenge is to
select the right ones to feel the also
dimdim also you have to categorize them
and good rules don't just throw you with
numbers they categorize present them in
a way that you can use them in a useful
way but I think nevertheless they are
important because you have to do some
measurement how your software evolves
over the time and I think at the moment
lots of people are not doing this at all
is it fair to say that the real value of
metrics is not their absolute number but
how they evolve over time you know is it
bad that you have a cyclomatic
complexity of 7 or should it be 11
or is it 11 already bad should it only
be 5 isn't it more interesting to see
that yesterday we hit 5 now we have 7
tomorrow we have 9 is it the trend that
is more important there is the absolute
number because I tend to think it's the
trend the trend is of course also
important but I think the absolute
number also says something about your
class so my experience was that outliers
usually were also candidates the cost
lot of design problems or maintenance
problems of course there may be some
good reason why there is such a number
and more advanced tools can even define
our own quality model so depending on
your project you can adjust the values
or depending on the programming language
or component infrastructure you're using
our example eg B ba ba etc you can adapt
those numbers and filter out things that
you're not interested in and the tools
are able to monitor things over time but
I guess that's the next point I think
most of the tools are evil and I
recommend that you only use something
that when it was that overtime I think
that was probably a really good bridge
to the next topic which is monitoring
changes so the idea is to see the trends
and as we saw in the last topic about
metrics it also influences your quality
now so with monitoring over time you can
see what new artifacts are coming into
your project you also see new
dependencies new architecture violations
and the idea is to correct those
violations before they really burn into
the codebase yeah and it's the same
thing with testing right if you if the
test fails five minutes after you did
something bad you can still remember
what you did same thing here yeah also
interesting is I think that most
outsourcing projects I know of are not
monitoring such things at all so I think
it's a must have for controlling project
yeah I agree so I guess this was the
theoretical part what what the tools can
do and what you should
use them for the next part of the
discussion is looking at certain tools
we have evaluated a number of them and
we're going to talk a little bit about
your experiences you can distinguish
them with certain features for example
some tools have methods to describe
architecture roots other just display
the architecture as it is and you don't
have any means to formulate the
architecture they also differ in how
they present the results for example
numbers or graphical way the granularity
idea in the creation is also a topic now
if you see the violation right in your
Eclipse it's much more easy and also
things like automation is scriptable
home online ID integration let's define
the optimal tool right what you want is
you want to be able to define your own
architectural constraints but you want
very fancy graphical layout to make you
aware of what's going on you want trend
analysis you want idea integration
everyone to the tool to be easy to use
okay well yeah it's back free and fast
and all that yeah okay so some tools I
have looked at is for example so to
graph from a software tomography yeah
that's a company we mentioned before I
want a picture spec is my CTO and they
recently merged with so notch a company
is called hello tomorrow right so that's
an interesting merger because as we'll
see one tool is more developer centric
IDE and the other is more for the
architect in a standalone version okay
so I think it's good manager next one is
a powerhouse XE beyond
it's been off of university uh-huh
hence talk to 101 from headway software
latex
clockworks is not mainly architecture
analysis tool it's more a lint like tool
yeah I know we've had it on the list on
the static analysis episode but it has
also a small part where you can
formulate or discover I should take this
time and there are a bunch of open
source projects we should mention
Xstrata semi-cold code or C soft etc so
um okay
which one do you wanna of course first
we should mention there even some basic
approach that you don't you can do
something without tool support to avoid
architectural decay
for example maintain your make system
and look which dependencies you have and
of course on a very coarse level there
are some simple tools like make depend
change and for example IDE specific
solutions like the Eclipse Java build
path where you can enter patterns for
packages that you can use on enemies
from from how you talk it sounds like
you mostly work with Java or the tool
Java specific or are they generally
language independent and no most of the
tools support some kind of Java and C
C++ I'm a sharp okay so the typical the
typical stuff some also support
additional language okay so so to graph
first one surah kahf is in my opinion a
very powerful tool it's one of the most
advanced but also a complex tool so you
have some time to get used to it it
displays the info Swire graphs and why
numbers it has some really useful layout
algorithms and it's known since eyes in
2003 and as we said the former sleepless
blast guy Walter bishops back as one of
the main implementers and designers of
Soto graph so there's some deep
knowledge in their area the data is
stored in
my SQL database you can you can access
that it's the open schema we access
that's with a phat GUI client written in
Java there's a sort of graph and it's
Toto arc so to artisan you tool which is
was invented 2007 it's more user
friendly
and you have also a rep report and a
bunch of metrics are 200 trend analysis
virtual refactoring and parser for C C++
Java and c-sharp and it disadvantages
except for the time it takes to get into
it it's very powerful and then that's
also one of the disadvantages so you can
get lost for example in too much matrix
so you have it to know where you want to
look at can you give us a feeling of the
language that's used to define the
architectures is something OCLs or how
does it feel you know this this
constraint definition language thing
actually there are two tools Soto craft
and so to arc in so to graph you use
some kind of Java language it was the
Java Bean shell where described which
components are composed from which write
packages and to which layer they are
loud and then you can define the
constraints and this was checked against
information in the database now we so
talk you don't do that anymore in soon
to do that graphically things and yeah
and the description is actually
generated into the former Soto
so in other words Soto arc is a
graphical user interface to graphically
define the specifications that formerly
wrote manual in soda cracker right okay
next one is the what is it the Bauhaus
suite our house read is from axion axion
is a spin-off of university student
university raymond the tool itself is
similar to a photograph in many points
one difference it's not database based
it's more file based and it has not so
easy user interface advantage is it
supports more languages but also other
COBOL with a basic and the tool itself
it's written in other maybe that's also
in other so maybe that's the reason that
a GUI is not so nice at the moment are
however a school Python scripting so you
can integrate that in your continuous
build process and mail for example
things you find out it's supports usual
things we discuss architectural
violation is checking metrics clone
detection cycle detection dead code
detection the difference to sort of
office that you even can define
architectural rules on a more fine level
that might be the macro level man yep so
not Jane so not J is f it is Java
central tool right only it has no graphs
and it's let's call it in memory DB so
it has essentially no no MySQL database
everything is kept in memory
it's very developer centric so it's a
Eclipse plug-in and the architecture
meta model is also manifested in the in
the tool itself so you have the vertical
and the horizontal layer and you divide
the technical part in the horizontal and
this is part in the vertically so but so
but the layers themselves are user
definable they are you okay so it just
has so much what's baked in the tool is
the matrix basically but not the
specific set of layers like data access
UI okay that's not okay and it has some
basic support for complexity check so
they're not so much metrics but you can
set some thresholds there's no trend
support at the moment
as I said week week metric support but
it's a very developer oriented and it's
as I said it's a Eclipse plugin and you
get immediate feedback from the
violations you are coding into the
source base and that's compared to Soto
graph where you basically you know you
pour the source code into it it works
for an hour and then gives you a bunch
of diagrams yeah so next one is
structure 101 that company in the US and
Ireland they have a standalone client
which is Java based supporting languages
like Java and C++ in cooperation with
quality qualities aesthetic analysis
code analyzer and programming research
is producing UAC so they're in
cooperation with them and I think ADA
version is planned also results are
represented as dependency structure
matrix as analytics numbers in matrix
and also in a graphical way what's
interesting is they have also a web
application called structure one one
tracker and they have even some
repository on their website where they
analyze open source the architecture of
open source projects so at the moment I
think you find about 10 or 20 projects
which are checked the other regularly
based it's the same approach that
cohered he does with static analysis of
en C++ code for open source projects
with the scan initiative and and and
while they're doing it is it to show off
their tool or is it to do a favor for
the open source tools to do them a favor
and and tell them what their problems
are I think it's both maybe more the
first topic to gain more visibility but
I think it's a good idea to offer this
for open source projects free and even
spring for example is a well-known
framework in java enterprise market and
spring for example is check
with sort of graph and solo J okay okay
relax
latex is essentially based on numbers so
you have no traffic's support also the
import is some importing source code is
some kind of weak in my opinion you have
no real C++ browser for example Stan why
dr. Chen or Microsoft PST files with
just very platform dependent no real
database in memory you get some kind you
can realize some kind of trend support
if you build it yourself why a
command-line so it's not that built in
however some people are using it and for
I think for simple projects and for
projects with a clean architecture it it
scales but for really grown project with
lots of violations it's difficult to use
so the idea is to have a matrix and that
matrix you say who is depending on me
and the column shows using relations and
the road shows used by well and then you
can group the artifacts in subsystem and
layers and arrange them in the in the
matrix AF also an example where they
show the architect of the and make tool
which is known and the interesting fact
is even in art there are where are some
violations over time despite the fact
that it's reviewed by lots of lots of
people here yeah clockwork clockwork is
not an architectural analysis tool in
the first place it's known for its data
code analysis capability but it's has
been extended and it's this place also
the things via graphs and tables
the layout algorithms are very weak at
the moment so there's no out-of-the-box
functionality where you can say arrange
this was the spring embed our algorithm
was things like that but you can
implement it yourself
why are ticking scripts which is not an
optimal approach in mind you say I shall
implement implement my own layout
algorithm in tickle node filtering of
the oh okay the filtering of the
information right will be implemented in
pickle and I think they rely on
consulting to do that and our customer
side it supports Java and C++ it's also
fed quick mind and what I have a rep rep
report of course there are some some
open source tools as I mentioned semi
code is at the moment also coming up
it's a Java only solution and that's so
performant at the moment but we'll see
how that evolves in over time also even
Google has some additional plugins for
JD pent to formulate rules so they are
also some some open source alternatives
however I should mention our experience
was it took us one week to get the
numbers YJ depend and sort them out to
get an overview of the of a real
existing Java application and in the
same time with another architectural
analysis tool we were able to refactor
and remove most of the violations in the
tool we were saying that it probably is
a good investment to buy the commercial
tool because the open-source tools
aren't area and there yet is any piece
of I think very quick however you have
to obey the learning curve at let's
start up ok so let's wrap this up with a
couple of take-home points so I think
today's IDE and build mechanisms are not
tweeted for architectural and unless you
have some basic support some open-source
tools like che depend but in my opinion
if you do real stuff and want to keep an
eye on the an architect and
maintainability of your application you
should use architectural analysis tool
so tools support I think is very
important the same with coding
guidelines you can have your ten pages
coding guideline and nobody reads it I
have to check this and enforce it
automatically otherwise it's just the
documents and laying around I think
although the management can be convinced
if existing problems become visible it's
a important point I think the quality of
architecture internal software quality
doesn't pay immediately based on the
long term and it's difficult to convince
the management to invest in internal
quality and unfortunately the topic
comes up when usually when it's too late
sweaters education is not maintainable
at all or when you want to remove some
module and you
that much I think is behind yes yeah all
the rules will and can be violated
that's also a good reason for that we
talked about interfaces have been
released to to client customers and then
you can say okay this world will there
is a deviation I accept this and don't
bother anymore so the tools are able to
remember that I don't want to be
bothered anymore you check something and
then it goes away it's not going up
again right okay so somehow thank you
very much for being on the show thank
you thanks for downloading and listening
to software engineering radio software
engineering radio is an educational
program brought to you by hillside
Europe if you want more information
about the podcast and all the other
episodes visit our website at st - radio
dot length if you want to support us you
can donate to the SU radio team via the
website or you can advertise for su
radio for example by clicking on the
Digg reddit delicious and Slashdot
buttons to contact the team please send
email to team at s e - radio net or if
it is specific to an episode please use
the comments facility on the website so
other people can react to your comments
this episode of se radio as well as all
other episodes are licensed under
creative commons 2.5 license please see
the website for details thanks to
Charlie Crowell and the pod safe music
network for the music used in the show
the song is called Vegas hard rock
shuffle
[Music]
you